What's going on, Kyle? Isaiah Smalls
from the Miami Herald. How are you?
>> I'm doing good. Just got done working
out.
>> That's what's up. That's That's what we
want to hear. That's what we want to
hear. Um, a lot of evaluators, you know,
have you pegged as a safety? I know you
played linebacker. I'm curious, where do
you feel the most at home?
>> I feel the most at home at linebacker. I
feel the most at home going against
tight ends at linebacker, going against
running backs at linebacker, being a
lineman at linebacker, and then, you
know, passing downs, packages, or heavy
rundowns. I could definitely play the
nickel ro when needed.
>> That's what's up. That's what's up. You
mentioned the coverage. You know, you
were one of my favorite players to watch
at the Senior Bowl because of your
coverage. Just talk to me a little bit
in general about your approach to
coverage and, you know, why do you excel
in that area?
>> I take pride in coverage. Like I grew up
always doing one v1. So I always take
pride in not losing even though like
it's obviously advantage for the
offense. Um I take pride in just not
losing one v ones. That that's that
don't go just for coverage. Just pass
coverage one-on- ones. Uh pass rush 101
ones. I take I take pride in all that.
>> Cool. Appreciate you, man.
Congratulations.
>> Appreciate you.
>> David.
>> Hey Kyle. Congratulations and welcome to
South Florida. David Feronus of South
Florida Sunseno. How you doing?
>> I'm doing good.
>> Good. Good. Uh, so I understand you were
a safety in high school, then converted
to linebacker. Do I have that right? And
then so I wonder how you feel your
safety traits and experience uh helped
you play at linebacker. Is it exactly uh
what you were mentioning uh your your
coverage abilities at the position?
>> Yeah, definitely was a smooth transition
for my cover abilities. I had to learn
more so on how linemen work, how to
engage linemen, how to run run block
linemen, defeat them. So, it's really
just a growing off that.
>> And the other thing I want to ask you is
a lot of people thought you were going
to go on day two, maybe third round,
etc. Uh, is there motivation for you
that you fell into day three and then
ended up with the Dolphins here in in
the fourth round?
It's definitely motivation and most
importantly it's just I think I thank
God for humbling humbling me in that
way. So I'm come in hungry for sure.
>> Awesome. Appreciate it. Thank you
>> Chris.
>> Hey Kyle Chris Perk and South Florida
Sun Sentinel. How you doing?
>> I'm doing good.
>> Hey uh I I was asking Trey Moore this.
You guys are both versatile players. If
you could draw up a role an ideal role
for yourself this season uh what would
it be?
ideal role for me is playing the will
linebacker spot and
having different coverage
responsibilities. I say that.
>> And and um as far as the the NFL, what
do you think your skill what what skill
translates best for you? I mean a a
tangible skill, whether it's running,
coverage, blocking, I mean a uh beating
blocks. What what what tangible skill
works best for you? Do you think?
My best tangible skills is
I still got to go with my covers, my my
instincts, not just man on man, but zone
coverage as well. Mass coverage.
>> All right, cool. Okay, thanks, Kyle.
Thanks.
>> Appreciate you,
>> Travis.
>> Hey, what's up, Kyle? My name is Travis.
I work for the Dolphins here.
Congratulations and welcome to South
Florida, man.
>> Thank you. Appreciate you.
>> I wanted to ask you about the senior
bowl week. I know you were one of the
big practice players of the week down
there. The Dolphins took a few guys from
that game. What did you learn that week
about your potential pro career and just
uh meeting with the Dolphins that week?
>> Funniest thing is the main thing I
learned is just
growing off uh the people that was in
the room with me. So, big shout out to
J-Rod. Just got close with him and we
were just feeding football to each
other, feeding off each other energy.
>> And you talked a little bit about your
one-on-one ability, man. I don't think
I've ever seen anybody have that much
success in those one-on-one coverage
drills because you got the whole field
to defend and you're running the routes
for guys most of the time. Is that like
a natural instincts thing for you? Is
that a case of repping it thousands of
time in your life? Like how did you get
so adept at feeling leverage and driving
on routes like that in coverage?
>> Yeah, it's thousand reps. Thousand reps.
Just knowing when the running back got
an option route, knowing how to play it.
Just thousand reps. Doesn't work.
>> All right. Appreciate you, Kyle. Thanks,
man.
>> Thank you. Appreciate you,
>> Joe.
>> Hey, Kyle. It's Joe in Palm Beach. Nice
to meet you.
>> Nice to meet you. Um, one of the things
that I thought was interesting, I read
that both you and Jacob Rodriguez, the
other linebacker that was drafted, um,
are um, dedicated to film study. So, I'm
curious, what is the most valuable thing
you've been taught or told about getting
the most out of film watching?
>> Most valuable thing I got taught by my
coach. He taught me how to use the
computer and how to dissect formation.
So definitely formation recognition and
then recently I've been having more keys
on line communication in terms of how
they going to slide pass block and
things such as that cuz school I'm from
we heavy bliss school.
>> That's really good stuff. Um take me
even a little deeper when you watch
opponent film. Um, do you do you get
more out of watching with coaches and
teammates or do you also do something
special when you watch by yourself in
terms of what you're looking for
>> to get the basics? I I really like
watching film by myself and then
watching film my teammates, my coaches,
I I pick up some tendencies that they do
that's different from teams I usually
face.
>> Perfect. Thanks, man. Look forward to
meeting you.
>> No problem. Appreciate you,
>> Travis.
>> Hey, Kyle, I got one more for you. You
mentioned playing with JR at the Senior
Bowl. Can you just tell us what you took
away from him and what you learned about
his game when you were there?
>> I know. I learned how to punch that ball
out. We was talking about how punching
the ball out all the time. And then, you
know, he did it he did it like probably
three times day two. So, just seeing
seeing him do it person, I'm like,
"Yeah, he he real with it. He legit with
it." And then, uh, you know, you got
your you got your losses that come with
punching the ball. You can't tell locker
room. His his whole knuckles is just
swollen. So yeah, you definitely
definitely got some causes with it. So
when you punch, you better get that ball
out.